

Profile

Experienced and dedicated Data Analyst with extensive experience identifying efficiencies and problem areas within data streams, while communicating needs for projects. Adept at receiving and monitoring data from multiple data streams, including SQL, and Excel data sources. Sound knowledge of Economics and statistical techniques, required for better understanding of business problems. Bringing forth the ability to synthesize quantitative information and interact effectively with colleagues and clients.

Education

Master of Science, University of Milan, Milano

September 2019 — Present

Pursuing Master degree in Data Science and Economics.

Doctor of Science in Economics, University of Helsinki, Helsinki

August 2015 — January 2018

Completed 3 years in Phd and currently in the research phase.

Master of Science, University of Kalyani, Kolkata

August 2012 — July 2014

Competed M.Sc in Economics with specializations in Econometrics and Environmental Economics.

Acquired 1st rank in the university.

Bachelor of Science, West Bengal State University, Kolkata

September 2009 — July 2012

Major in Economics with Mathematics and statistics.

Acquired 1st rank in college and 5th rank in the university.

Internships

Data Science Intern at Innodatatics, Bengaluru

June 2021 — December 2021

- Responsible for gathering requirements from Business Owners and identifying trends in data using exploratory data analysis.
- Performed data processing from various sources and responsible to create a dashboard using Power BI to showcase the findings.
- Extracted, analyzed and presented data in graphical format and presented it to the team for better understanding of the data.
- Proficient in importing and exporting large amount of data using SQL and python libraries.
- Used inner and outer join to combine data while importing data from multiple tables.
- Designed and developed dashboard on Sales insight data of client company using different aggregated functions.

Details

India

+917003653448

debanjali.eco@gmail.com

Links

Linkedin GitHub Portfolio

Skills

Data Analysis

Python

Machine Learning

SQL

Strong Analytical Skills

Econometrics

Statistics

Time series Analysis

Languages

English

Bengali

Hindi

Italian

Hobbies

Painting, Dancing, Baking, yoga

- Data Visualization using wide variety of chats, tables, plots, maps, dashboards.
- Strong hands-on experience on Python and data science/analysis libraries (Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, seaborn, Matplotlib, scipy, etc).
- Experienced in Natural Language Processing(NLP) with NLTK, Spacy libraries.
- Experienced in SQL gold badge from HackerRank and extensive experience with multiple SQL projects.

Employment History

Data Analytics Freelancer at Upwork

January 2022

- Effectively scraped unstructured data.
- Performed exploratory data analysis and discovered notable relationships.
- Worked to assess the business needs and resolved issues with the use of data.
- Analyzed data by creating dashboards to understand sales insights of company and access areas of improvement.

Teaching Assistant at University of Helsinki, Helsinki

August 2017 — December 2017

Conducting exercise classes of PhD and Master degree students.

- Helped students with concepts of macroeconomic theory and problems on mathematical economics.
- Designing class materials and giving feedback on student performance.

Research Assistant at Hanken School of Economics, Helsinki

May 2015 — August 2016

Worked on a project based on implementation of solar electricity in Finland under Dr. Jaakko Aspara.

- Conducted marketing research to accurately identify industry trends and business opportunities.
- Building questionnaire for conducting a market survey to help identify potential customers and market conditions.
- Helped to devise a new business model, and steps to support it.

Certifications

Databases and SQL for Data Science - IBM

May 2019

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/APNTFEFA4X3V

Data Science Certification by ExcelR Solutions

January 2021 — June 2021